raileurope.com 2019-07-31

# None

  * #### Home

### Privacy Policy

Rail Europe North America, Inc. (“Rail Europe,” “we,” “us” and “our”) respects your privacy and we want you to understand the ways in which we collect and use information about you. This Privacy Policy applies to information you provide to Rail Europe through our website, via RailEurope.com, raileurope.ca or raileurope.mx (“RailEurope.com Site”), through Rail Europe mobile applications, or over the phone to Rail Europe employees. Please review this Privacy Policy carefully. You are agreeing to its terms by visiting or using RailEurope.com Site. Notice of all changes that materially affect ways in which your personally identifiable information may be used or shared will be posted in updates to our Privacy Policy. If you continue to use the RailEurope.com Site after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on RailEurope.com Site, you hereby provide your consent to the changed practices.  
Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to information that our affiliates may collect, or for use of our websites outside of the jurisdiction noted in our Terms of Use. Please visit any such other site, as applicable, in order to review those policies and manage your communication preferences.

### Collection, Use, and Accessing of Information

**Information Collection**

Whether you make a purchase, register for an account, or are just a visitor, we are very careful with what we do with your information. Collection of information is usually grouped into two categories: personally identifiable, which is information identifiable to a specific user, and non-personally identifiable, which is defined by this Privacy Policy as general demographic information (gender, age, zip code), as well as RailEurope.com Site-wide usage information (route and destination popularity, pages visited, promotion participation levels), device, browser, and geo-location.

We collect non-personally identifiable information when it is affirmatively provided or passively when you use our website or mobile applications. We may use non-personally identifiable information for any purpose or disclose it to anyone. Where the two categories of information are combined, the resulting information is treated as personally identifiable information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

In order to provide our services, including obtaining rail tickets on your behalf, we must, by necessity, coordinate with, and provide some of your personal information to, companies in the EU and North America that we do not control. As a result, your personal information may be stored or processed on computers located outside your jurisdiction of residence, and in jurisdictions whose data protection laws may differ from the jurisdiction in which you live. This information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement officials and national security authorities in those jurisdictions according to laws in those jurisdictions.

In many cases, you can view the RailEurope.com Site without telling us who you are or revealing any personally identifiable information. However, if you wish to purchase a rail pass or other ticket, you will have to provide information required of any traveler. This includes your name, and your email address, as well as the names of anyone traveling with you. If you select an age-specific ticket or pass, such as “youth” or “senior,” you also must provide your age group and that of anyone traveling with you, as applicable. Further, you must provide us with your valid payment information, including credit card numbers and expirations dates (all such foregoing information, collectively, “Data”).  
Since Rail Europe is only the distributor of products and services provided by third parties (“Suppliers”), we also are collecting your Data on behalf of those Suppliers. For example, these Suppliers will need each traveler’s name and age group for identification purposes and to verify that each pass or other ticket is being used in accordance with that Supplier’s terms and conditions. Our collection of and disclosure of your Data is a required part of your transaction, and you agree by engaging in such transactions on the RailEurope.com Site to such collection and disclosure.

If you make purchases with us often, you may want to set up an account with us by registering on the RailEurope.com Site. This will make it easier for you to complete your purchases quickly. As a registered RailEurope.com Site user, you also may elect to receive newsletters and similar emails from us with travel news and information. Registered users of the RailEurope.com Site should be mindful of password-entry requirements and not disclose account numbers or passwords to others. Please read the Terms of Use for further information about your rights and responsibilities in maintaining an account with us.

Apart from purchases and registration, from time-to-time, we also request information via surveys, contests, in sweepstakes or other promotions, polls, and you may send questions or comments to us via email. In such cases, we will collect personally identifiable information when you choose to participate in sweepstakes or other promotions, fill out surveys, complete polls, or send questions or comments to us via email. Please read below for more information on how we use information collected through these means. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring the use of this site and improving customer satisfaction. Participation in these activities is completely voluntary and you may choose whether or not to participate and therefore disclose this information.

We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13, and require that those making purchases on the RailEurope.com Site be 18 years of age or older and the age of legal majority in the jurisdiction where they reside. Should a child whom we know to be under 13 send personal information to us, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child to inform him or her that we must have parental consent before receiving his or her personal information. Each travel product or service also may be subject to age restrictions, and we reserve the right to impose further restrictions on those or similar purchases.

**Data Use for Transactional and Promotional Purposes by Rail Europe**

We and our service providers who assist us in connection with RailEurope.com Site operations may retain and use Data and other personally identifiable information, as well as non-personally identifiable information, in providing the RailEurope.com Site to you, which uses may include, without limitation, the following:

    * to facilitate your purchases of rail, car and travel passes and other ticketed travel products and services that we distribute;
    * to complete your travel-product purchase transactions by disclosing your Data to our Suppliers
    * to administer such purchases and provide reminders and follow-up information regarding your purchases and travel plans;
    * to send you email newsletters, at a registered RailEurope.com Site user’s election, about Rail Europe and the many exciting destinations to which we offer travel;
    * to allow participation in our various promotional programs, including sweepstakes and contests, that we may offer from time to time;
    * to inform you of other types of services we or our Suppliers offer;
    * to respond to your inquiries or requests, including your customer service needs;
    * to improve RailEurope.com Site, including after research and analysis, for future marketing and/or promotional use about us or the products, services and features we may offer;
    * to survey visitors about various topics, including their views on travel, destination preferences, and what further travel information we might provide; and,
    * for any other purpose disclosed to you at the time you are asked to submit your personally identifiable information.

**Information Uses Involving Third Parties**

As noted above, Rail Europe is a distributor of our Suppliers’ products and services, and, as a required part of travel, each of our Suppliers must have access to the names and age groups of each traveler for whom a pass or other ticket is purchased for its product or service. We do not provide this information to our Suppliers for their direct marketing purposes, and to our knowledge and belief, our Suppliers do not use the personal information we provide to them for reasons other than completing your travel-related transactions.

Rail Europe also provides services through various referral partners and travel agencies. If you enter the RailEurope.com Site from the site of one of our marketing or referral partners, our system may recognize the path you have taken. Once you have left a partner’s site and/or begin the purchase transaction on RailEurope.com Site, those partners do not have access to the personal information you provide through our Site. Such information is treated as Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We also may track the path you have taken, combined with what purchases you may make, to gauge the success of our online marketing and promotional campaigns.

In addition to purchasing tickets through the RailEurope.com Site, you may have an opportunity to provide information directly to our marketing or referral partners, whether through the RailEurope.com Site or on a partner’s web site, or to third parties who merely maintain links on the RailEurope.com Site. These third parties may maintain separate privacy policies governing the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information, which you should review for more information. Once you leave the RailEurope.com Site, use of any information you provide will be governed by the privacy policy of that site’s operator. We, our parent companies, affiliates and subsidiaries are not responsible for the collection, use and disclosure practices with respect to personally identifiable and other information of third parties.

As noted, from time to time, we may survey you for your opinion, offer participation in sweepstakes, and conduct reviews to enhance the RailEurope.com Site. We also send you newsletters to which you have subscribed. For each of these, we may rely on service providers to help us collect and analyze research, administer the sweepstakes, and provide technical support in sending the newsletters and other, similar emails. We do not disclose any Data included in this information for such providers’ direct marketing purposes, nor so they may pass it on to others for the same reasons.

**Information Use for Site Operations, Corporate and Legal Compliance**

We may use or disclose your personally identifiable information as is permitted by this Privacy Policy, or according to the Terms of Use. This includes:

    * performing standard business operations, such as transaction, payment processing, billing, collections, and accounting
    * protecting our and our content providers’ business interests, including ensuring RailEurope.com Site operation and adherence to the Terms of Use and Usage Rules;
    * investigating or helping to prevent unlawful activity or activity that may threaten our visitors, users, employees, or property; and
    * in cooperating with law-enforcement investigations, or as required by law or by, subpoena, warrant, or other order of the court or governmental agency;
    * to prevent harm to person or property;
    * from time to time we may transfer information to our Affiliates in France in order to provide the services;

To help us perform these functions, we may retain third parties to whom we disclose personal information. These third parties include our customer-service providers, who handle your inquiries and store your Data; credit-card, debit-card and similar transaction processors; technical-service providers or similar entities that maintain the RailEurope.com Site operations; attorneys; accountants; auditors; and authorized government entities or other lawfully authorized parties. We may also disclose your personal and other information to our parent companies, affiliates or subsidiaries; content providers; and to third parties in conjunction with the reorganization or sale of our stock or assets, or if we are involved in bankruptcy proceedings. We will do so only after taking steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected. Any third party to which we transfer or sell our assets will have the right to continue to use the personal and other information that you provided to us.

**Access to Your Personal Information**

If you have registered on RailEurope.com Site, you may view and update your account information at any time, as well as manage your account and communication preferences. Please visit “My Account” or click here. If you have not registered with the RailEurope.com Site, and/or need to update your Data for a pending trip, please contact us using the Contact Us page. If you have completed travel, and are not a registered user, you most likely need not update your Data unless and until you enter into a new purchase transaction with us. For questions about this or other questions about your information, please email myaccount@raileurope.com.

### Online Technology and Security

**Cookie Use, Tracking Technologies, Digital-Media Player Software and Screen Sharing Software**  
A browser cookie is a small text file that is sent to an end-user’s browser and is used to remember you when you return to the site or browse through our Site. When you browse our Site, you will also be sent “3rd party cookies” which are cookies used by entities that provide RENA with analytics, advertising, or other functions. These 3rd party cookies may be re-transmitted to 3rd parties as you browse the web. They do not transmit personally identifiable information from your browsing session on our website, but may be used to target advertising as you browse other parts of the web. Most browsers allow you to control browser cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. You can set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser. However, please be aware that some features of RailEurope.com Site may not function properly if you refuse cookies.

Our cookies are typically session-oriented, or we use them to store info you’ve placed in a shopping cart when you visit our site during a select period of time. We also may use cookies to see what pages have been accessed and how frequently. Our tracking technologies also may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; clickstream patterns; and dates and times that the RailEurope.com Site is accessed.

Rail Europe uses various ad networks to show online advertising on third party websites to users that have visited our website. When you visit the Rail Europe website, these ad networks such as Google will set a cookie identifying your browser software as having visited Rail Europe. When you visit another website that is also part of an ad network to whom Rail Europe subscribes to, you may see advertising targeted to your browser, based on actions you have taken while visiting the Rail Europe website.  
Information on your activity on the Rail Europe website used by third parties to show personalized ads is stored on a cookie on your computer. Rail Europe doesn’t have access to those cookies and cannot use the information it contains.

If you do not wish to see those customized ads served by Google, you can update your preferences by visiting <https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/>

If you do not wish to view any type of personalized ads from any ad network participating in the Network Advertising Initiative, you may opt out at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

Rail Europe also uses a technology known as Dynamic Ad Serving which enables us to customize the content of certain online ads based on the activity you have taken on our website. This technology uses the Teracent Cookie. If you do not wish to see such ads, you can opt out by visiting <http://www.teracent.com/about-us/opt-out>

Rail Europe also uses the DoubleClick allowing us to serve ads on other sites to users that have previously visited our website. If you do not wish to see those ads, please visit the DoubleClick opt-out page or the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

Rail Europe may also use other 3rd parties and technologies, other than those listed on this website, for advertising, analytics, and to deliver content. Some of these technologies may use local shared objects or “flash cookies,” or other technologies that cannot be managed by changing browser settings. Our advertising, analytics, or content partners may also use “web beacons” which may not be managed or fully blocked by altering your browser settings.

We may occasionally assist you with technical issues in connection with your access and/or use of the RailEurope.com Site via third party provider screen sharing technology solutions. The use of such technologies will allow us to remotely view and access your computer screen, in all cases with your prior approval in granting us such access right so we may assist you with such issues. Any such remote access will be discontinued immediately upon the resolution of any such issue. We disclaim any liability in connection with any issue that may result from such assistance and the use of any such technology solutions.

**Call Center**

When you call us or, when we call you, we record the communication in order to enable better customer service. We store this information for no more than one year.

**Use of Cloud Services**

In order to carry out certain of our business functions, we make use of computer resources in “cloud” data centers. Therefore maybe subject to different set of terms and conditions.

**Security of Personal Information**

Wherever your Data may be held by us or on our behalf, we intend to take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect it from unauthorized access or disclosure. Your Data is encrypted as it is transmitted over the Internet from your desktop computer or portable device to our servers. If you have registered with us, your information is stored behind a “firewall” (a combination of computer hardware and software that helps keep unauthorized visitors from accessing information within our computer network), and your financial information, such as your credit card number, is encrypted as well. Unfortunately, no database or data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to us online and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction or inadvertent disclosure of your personal information.

**Data Breach**

When you register for a RailEurope.com Site account, you agree that you will not allow others to use your account or Data, and, except as expressly stated in this Privacy Policy, you are solely and entirely responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of both. Furthermore, you are solely and entirely responsible for any and all activities that occur under your account and you agree to immediately notify us at privacy@raileurope.com of any unauthorized use or breach of your account or any other breach of security. Please refer to the Terms of Use for more information on your responsibilities in maintaining and protecting your Data.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any comments or questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us at legal@raileurope.com, or at our contact information below. While we cannot guarantee privacy perfection, we will address any issue to the best of our abilities as soon as possible.

  * #### What is your data used for?

Rail Europe only collects and uses data concerning you for purposes that are precise and limited to what is necessary for you, namely:

● **processing your orders:**

— enabling carriers and travel partners to provide you with services ordered,   
— ensuring payment for the products that you have purchased,   
— providing assistance to users of Rail Europe sites by email, or chat, when they request assistance for an order, for connecting to the sites or accessing their customer accounts,   
— monitoring and providing after sales service for products ordered (information, cancellations, reimbursements, exchange, complaints),   
— helping making orders: if you do not complete an order made on the Rail Europe site, Rail Europe may send you an email offering its help;

● **managing your customer account:** at Rail Europe, the customer account is not mandatory. However, it is very useful because it is an account that is entirely dedicated to you and makes it easy for you to:

— easily give orders (automatic entry of your data: identification and travel preferences),   
— access your order data;

● **communicate with you:** for Rail Europe, maintaining contact with you is essential, but we only do it in a carefully controlled manner and we only send you electronic communications, via email, SMS or mobile notification, for the following reasons:

—  _monitoring orders:_ sending confirmations of orders and any other messages related to the service that you have ordered,   
—  _the management of your customer account:_ confirmation of creation or closure, modification of passwords,   
—  _making commercial offers:_ only in one of the following two cases:

□ if you are registered for the "Newsletter" service from Rail Europe,  
□ if you have ordered products on the Rail Europe site or the Rail Europe mobile application.

In all cases, you may unsubscribe from our commercial newsletter service by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of the newsletters,   
—  _rewarding of your loyalty:_ Rail Europe may occasionally present offers to reward your loyalty;

● **offering you personalised products and services:** at Rail Europe, we are intent on constantly offering you products that are most likely to be suitable for you. At Rail Europe, we offer you personalised content:

— in the commercial communications that we send to you,   
— when you browse the Rail Europe sites,   
— through certain services using geolocation (only on the Rail Europe mobile application),   
— via targeted and personalised advertising banners on other sites;

● **fighting fraud:** the security and proper functioning of our sites is a major issue. The data is analysed automatically by our subcontractor to determine a level of fraud risk associated with each order.  
The analysis criteria include the browsing behaviour, the data related to the terminal used and the bank details

According to the results of this risk analysis, and after a check by our anti-fraud teams, Rail Europe may do one of the following:

— validate your order;   
— request additional substantiating documentation;   
— refuse the order;   
— cancel the order and reimburse the funds.

In case of any confirmed problem with an order, or in the case of an outstanding debt, your data will be written to an alert file belonging to Rail Europe, which may, for future orders, make additional checks.

You can, at any time, make a complaint or request information by contacting Rail Europe customer service.

● **offer you games/contests:** in this context, Rail Europe and/or its partners will use the data that you have agreed to communicate strictly for the purposes of implementing the game and communication. As part of games and contests, after you have registered and given your advance authorisation, you may be offered commercial offerings from time to time by third-party partners of Rail Europe.

  * #### What is our data management policy?

### What data do we collect?

At Rail Europe, we scrupulously follow the principle of "minimisation", meaning that we collect only the data that is strictly necessary to the purposes defined above, namely:  
● **identification data (name, email address, IP address)** > This data is essential for any orders, registration for a customer account or for the security of the sites and transactions of Rail Europe;  
● **banking data** > This data is essential for any orders or reimbursements;  
● **data related to your searches and your order (product purchased (destination, date, price,…))** > This data is essential to provide the ordered service and after-sales service;  
● **data related to your habits and centres of interest (favourite destinations, choice of additional services,…)** > This data is useful for making personalised offers;  
● **contact data (telephone no, email address, postal address)** > This data is useful to contact you if required (problem related to your order or a purchased product, travel information) or to send you your train tickets, either to your home or electronically;  
● **technical data:** during browsing, Rail Europe collects information such as the version of your browser, operating system used or the model of terminal used > This data is necessary for optimal display and functioning of Rail Europe sites and applications;  
● **browsing data (searches, number of visits, date of last visit,…)** > This data is useful for making commercial offers.

### How do we collect the data?

At Rail Europe, the sources of data are:  
● **You:**   
— when you complete forms on the Rail Europe sites and application,   
— when you browse Rail Europe sites and application (pages consulted, duration of consultation of pages),  
For each of them, you are informed of the data that is necessary and that which is optional, by asterisks on the entry forms.  
● **the technical information**   
— your IP address, the telecoms operator and the macroscopic location of the IP address,   
— the information provided by the browser on the operating system and the browser used,   
—  **cookies:** [see the chapter on cookies.](https://www.raileurope.com/cookies-policy/)

### How long is the data retained?

The data is only kept for periods that are strictly necessary:  
● _to the implementation of orders;_  
● _to legal and regulatory constraints,_ notably in matters of dispute management;  
● _to the provision of personalised services._  
The general data retention policy used by Rail Europe is as follows:   
● **identification data:** five years from the last visit to the site or connection to the service;  
● **order data:** five years from the date of the order;  
● **bank details:** maximum thirteen months in order to manage the after-sales service (reimbursements);  
● **prospect data:** one year after the date of the last activity on Rail Europe sites or the last opening of a newsletter;  
● **connection logs:** one year from each connection;  
● **cookies:** thirteen months maximum from them being saved on your computer or terminal.

### What resources are used to ensure the security of the data?

Rail Europe is particularly vigilant concerning the security of your data and devotes significant human and technical resources to protect it. A strict security policy is in place to define the processes, working methods and rules for technical protection to be used. The security measures used include, but are not limited to:  
● automated systems for protection against cyber-attacks are active;  
● computer code on the Rail Europe sites is subjected to security reviews;   
● automated tools periodically carry out security tests on the Rail Europe sites;  
● the security of Rail Europe sites is audited by companies that are experts in the subject;   
● personal data of customers is subject to strict access control;  
● experts in cyber security can intervene at any time to handle security incidents.

  * #### Is my data transferred to third parties?

### General framework

The policy of Rail Europe is very clear on this subject: Rail Europe does not transfer any data to third-party companies for any reason other than one of the following:  
● **supply of services ordered:** in order to be able to provide you with the transport or ancillary services offered, the data is transmitted to the companies concerned, namely:

—  **carriers:** rail carriers and their subsidiaries for associated service,   
—  **partners:** tourism product sold by partners, directly or under white label;

● **subcontracting:** Rail Europe uses contractors to operate its sites and provide you with the services and products proposed, and notably:

— Its IT subcontractors,   
— For the customer relationship: call centres, communication tools,   
— For payment: suppliers of partners offering products on the Rail Europe site,   
— For marketing services: marketing follow-up, dispatch of newsletters,   
— For the fight against fraud: specialist service provider;

For all of these transfers of data, Rail Europe takes strict care to:  
● only work with trusted companies;  
● secure its relationships with these companies.

### Transfers in foreign countries

Rail Europe transfers data in foreign countries for the following cases:  
● order processing: Rail Europe data centers are located in France and in China,  
● customer relationships: your data may be transferred to one of several call centres, that are located in France, USA, Argentina, India, Hong-Kong, Australia, New-Zealand, Singapore, Japan, South Korea, Israel and South Africa,  
● fraud prevention: subcontractor of Rail Europe, uses the data in the United States and in the Netherlands.

  * #### How can I exercise my rights?

### What are my rights?

You have the following rights concerning your data and the right to make sure that Rail Europe is compliant with its commitments.  
● **Right of access:** You may contact us to find out what data Rail Europe has concerning you;  
● **Right to correction and deletion:** You may correct data concerning you and request that it be deleted;  
● **Right of objection:** You may object to Rail Europe performing various processes;  
● **Right to portability:** You may request that Rail Europe sends you the data concerning you (identification and order data exclusively) in an electronic format (CSV file).   
It is nevertheless reiterated that the exercise of these rights is not absolute and may be limited for reasons of legitimate interest (customer dispute) or for legal reasons.

### How can I exercise my rights?

**Right of access, correction, deletion and portability:**

If you have a customer account, you can undertake these operations directly, by connecting to your customer account.  
● If not, you may send your requests to Rail Europe customer service using the following [ electronic form ](https://www.raileurope.com/spip.php?page=contact) or by letter to the following address: Rail Europe, Customer service, at 2 place de la Défense, CNIT 1, BP 440, 92053 Paris La Défense, France.

**Right of objection:**

You may exercise your right of objection as follows:  
● **for commercial newsletters:** by clicking the "unsubscribe" link mentioned in the newsletters that are sent to you > Rail Europe then undertakes not to send you any more commercial newsletters;  
● **for all other requests:** by sending your requests to Rail Europe customer service using the following electronic form (insert link) or by letter to the following address: Service Clients Rail Europe, Customer service, at 2 place de la Défense, CNIT 1, BP 440, 92053 Paris La Défense, France.

For all of these requests, and for security reasons, you will be asked to identify yourself and communicate a copy of your identity document to Rail Europe customer service.

### And how does it work for social networks?

The Rail Europe sites use plug-ins for social networks, notably Facebook, Twitter, Instagram... If you interact with these plug-ins (clicking the "Like" or "Share" buttons), the information related to your browsing and to the operations carried out on the Rail Europe sites will be sent to the company operating the social network in question.

**Also, if you do not want a social network to which you belong to link information collected when browsing on the Rail Europe sites, you must disconnect from the social network in question before visiting the Rail Europe sites.**

In all cases, the use of these plug-ins or the data collected when browsing with the social network activated is exclusively governed by the general conditions of the social networks concerned.

**We therefore invite you to read the personal data protection policies of these social networks to learn precisely what information is collected and how it is used.**

  * #### What is the policy of Rail Europe concerning cookies?

### What is a cookie?

These are files that are placed in the browser on your computer or terminal when you browse the Rail Europe site. These files are subsequently automatically sent by the browser to the servers of Rail Europe during your browsing, in order:  
● to enable browsing on the Rail Europe sites (management of shopping baskets, customer account connection sessions, proof of authentication for the "remember me" function, servers used, etc.) or to adapt to your terminal (language used, display resolution, operating system of the site);  
● to monitor customer browsing on the Rail Europe sites and to measure audiences to optimise and improve the sites;   
● to personalise the click path and the offers;  
● to manage advertising on the Rail Europe sites and other sites;

### Who are the cookies placed by?

These files are placed:  
● **Either by Rail Europe**  
● **Or by third parties:** When you browse the Rail Europe sites, cookies are issued by third-party companies (companies providing user help, advertising service providers, communications agency, audience measurement companies, etc.), subject to choices that you have made previously with their services, or at any time under the conditions described below.  
These cookies are mainly intended to provide you with advertising content likely to correspond to your centres of interest according to the data collected during your browsing on the Rail Europe site.  
These cookies may also enable:

— counting the number of displays of advertising content disseminated via the advertising spaces on the Rail Europe sites, identifying advertisements displayed and the number of users who clicked on each advertisement, in order to calculate amounts due and prepare statistics;   
— recognise your computer or terminal during your browsing on any other site in order to adapt the advertisements that are disseminated there;  
The issue and the use of these third-party cookies are subject to the confidentiality and data-protection policies of these third-party companies. However, we inform you, when we actually know, of the purpose of these cookies.  
Also, if your computer or terminal is used by several persons, or if it has several browsers, it is not possible for Rail Europe to be sure that the services and advertisements correspond to your use of Rail Europe sites and not that of another user. This choice of sharing and configuration is your free choice and responsibility.

### Detailed description of the cookies of Rail Europe: 

**Cookies for technical uses:**  
● browsing sessions (connection to customer account, technical browsing session, servers used);  
● simplification of the visit, with adaptation of display criteria to your computer or terminal (language used, display resolution, operating system, browser used, accessibility parameter);  
● detection of a previous visit;  
● registration of customer preferences;  
● automatic re-connection to the customer account (when activated).  
These cookies are necessary to the correct functioning of Rail Europe and to your browsing.

**Cookies used for monitoring:**

● audience measurement: statistical data on traffic and the use of the Rail Europe sites (sections and content targeted, click path) in order to measure and study the functioning and efficiency of Rail Europe sites, and thus improve the benefit and ergonomics of the services of Rail Europe;  
● comparative tests of several versions of the site.  
These cookies enable the continuous improvement of the sites and services of Rail Europe (benefits, ergonomics,…).

**Cookies for personalisation purposes:**

● personalisation, in real-time, of browsing on Rail Europe sites and proposal of relevant and personalised offers;  
● improvement of the ergonomics;   
● identification of browsing problems in order to offer the assistance of a call-centre agent.  
These cookies enable you to be offered products and services that are personalised and in accordance with your requirements and centres of interest.

**Cookies for advertising use:**

● counting and personalisation of content and advertisements proposed when you visit the Rail Europe sites;  
● connections to social network services, sharing information on social networks.  
These cookies enable the most relevant offers to be provided to you.   
A list of cookies is accessible in the section "Cookies "

How are they put in place?

When browsing the Rail Europe sites:   
● you are informed of the existence of cookies via the navigation banner that appears when you first visit or in case you delete the cookies placed by Rail Europe;  
● you consent to the placing and use of cookies by every browsing act.

### How do I express my choices concerning cookies?

You can configure your browsing with your browser: you can authorise or refuse the saving of cookies on your computer or terminal with the appropriate parameters of your browsing software.

These parameters are specific to each browser and are accessible via your browser’s help menu :

● [ Internet Explorer™](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)  
● [ Safari™](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=fr_CA&viewlocale=en_US)  
● [ Chrome™](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&hlrm=en)  
● [ Firefox ™](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences)  
● [ Opera™](https://help.opera.com/en/latest/web-preferences/#cookies)
